* LOGIN SIGN UP

#### New: WhatPulse for organizations! [Learn more here](https://whatpulse.pro/?ref=wporg).

Privacy Policy
==============

The following page outlines how WhatPulse uses and protects any information that you give WhatPulse when using this website or the software client.

WhatPulse is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. WhatPulse may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. By using any services of WhatPulse you agree to this privacy policy.

* * *

##### Information Collected

WhatPulse only collects information (be it via a website form or the software client) that is relevant to the purpose of our website. When you register for a WhatPulse account, we will ask you for your name (as provided) and valid e-mail address.

The software client collects statistics from your computer(s) as you direct it too. The types of statistics can vary and you have the ability to turn off each individual type of statistic. When you 'pulse' to our website, the software client will only send the data you have allowed it to send.

The information collected with the WhatPulse client is only used for analytics as shown on the website. Information linked to your account will never be sold or handed over to a third party. Only aggregated, anonymized data may be used for global analytics by third parties, on-site advertisements or marketing purposes.

In summary,

We collect relevant information so you can participate in our website and application. You have complete control what statistics are gathered. We don't sell your personal information and stats.

##### Analytical Cookies & Usage Data

At WhatPulse, we utilize Plausible Analytics, routed through our stats subdomain, on our website to gain insights into visitor behavior and assess the efficacy of our marketing efforts. We have selected Plausible Analytics due to its privacy-centric approach, which prioritizes anonymized aggregate data over personally identifiable information. No cookies are used and no personal data—not even an IP address or browser user agent—is stored. For more information on how Plausible Analytics handles data, please refer to their [Data Policy](https://plausible.io/data-policy).

On the WhatPulse client application, Plausible Analytics is used as the backend to process usage data. Similar to the website, we track aggregated behavior, such as what pages and sections you looked at, for how long, and so on. This data is completely anonymized by randomly generating a Client ID per installation, which is not linked to your account in any way. This information is important to us for improving the user experience and determining WhatPulse client effectiveness and helps us prioritize features. If you would like to stop the WhatPulse client from collecting and sending your usage data, please disable the option called **Send bug and usage reports**. [Click here for more information](https://whatpulse.org/help/docs/software/settings/client-bug-and-usage-reports) about the content, process, and usage of the data described here.

In summary,

We collect anonymized and aggregated data on the website and WhatPulse client, to see which parts of our products are being used. This information is important to us for improving the user experience and helps us prioritize features. You can disable this.

* * *

##### Keeping Information Safe

Your WhatPulse account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. This password is stored encrypted. Protect against unauthorized access to your account by logging off the website once you have finished using a shared computer. We encourage you to use a 2-Factor Authentication (2FA) method for additional security.

Only WhatPulse staff who need personal information to perform a specific task (upon your request) are granted access to it. All of our employees & relations are kept up to date on our privacy and security policies.

In summary,

Your account is protected by a password. We encrypt it, you must also keep it secure. Our staff may access your account only to do a specific (requested) task.

* * *

##### Third-Party Services - Payment Providers

WhatPulse uses Paddle as its payment provider to handle transactions for premium memberships. Paddle is a third-party service that securely processes payments and stores data related to those transactions, including order details, billing information, and other relevant data necessary to process and manage payments. In addition to processing payments, Paddle also provides notification to WhatPulse about premium memberships, so we can activate premium features for our users.

Further reading: [Paddle's Buyer Privacy Notice](https://www.paddle.com/legal/privacy)

Please note that we also previously used PayPal and Stripe as our legacy payment providers.

In summary,

We use third-party payment providers for Premium, which collect and process payment information.

* * *

##### Data Retention & Deletion

Your data will be available on the WhatPulse website and client as long as you have an account. You can delete your account at any time, which will delete all your data from our website. You can do this from your [account management page](https://whatpulse.org/dashboard/my/account). We will **not** keep any personal data when your account is deleted.

In summary,

You can delete your account at any time, deleting any personal information we have.

* * *

##### Policy Towards Children

You must be 13 or older to register a WhatPulse account. If you become aware that your child has provided WhatPulse with personal information without your consent, please contact us at [privacy@whatpulse.org](mailto:privacy@whatpulse.org). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without parental consent, we will take steps to remove such information.

In summary,

We allow 13 years and older. If you are younger than 18 years of age, please ask your parent for consent.

* * *

##### Changes to & Effective Date of this Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is effective as of 6 March, 2023. WhatPulse may update this Privacy Policy from time to time.

In summary,

Effective as of March 6th, 2023. We can change this to keep up to date.

© 2004-2024 WhatPulse.  
Made with ❤️ by [@smitmartijn](https://twitter.com/smitmartijn)  
All times are in 2024-12-12.

### Related Products

    WhatPulse for organizations and teams
    Never hear "hey, you're on mute" again
    Elevate your typing skills.

### WhatPulse

### Community

### About
